Guide to the Aubrey and Sylvia Farb Papers, 1938-2018 MS 741
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Aubrey and Sylvia Farb Papers
1938-2018
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Morris, Susan Farb
MS 741
.50 Linear Feet 1 box
This collection contains a small number of programs, certificates, booklets, an oral history recording and transcript, and correspondence regarding imminent Jewish Associations in Houston and Aubrey Farb's personal papers from 1938 to 2018.
Biographical / Historical
Married in May of 1948, Aubrey and Sylvia Farb are influential members of the Houston Jewish Community, making their mark by volunteering with politics, the arts, and the homeless. The Aubrey and Sylvia Farb Community Service Fund they created at Congregation Emanu El is still very active today. After marrying, they settled in Houston, and have 4 daughters, and 6 grandchildren.
A native of Galveston, Texas, Sylvia Farb was born on April 25, 1926. After graduating from the University of Texas at Austin, she moved to Houston, where she met her future husband playing bridge, a mutual hobby. She worked as a travel agent for Joske's Travel, spent some years as a stay-at-home mother, and volunteered in her free time.
Born September 1, 1922, Aubrey Farb moved from his hometown in Galveston to attend the Rice Institute (now Rice University) in Houston. During his school days, he was involved with the Menorah Society (a predecessor to Hillel) and served as a representative to the Student Religious Council. During the war, he was chosen to attend Japanese Language School, becoming a Japanese interrogation Officer, before returning to receive his Master's Degree from Columbia University. Farb then found work as a CPA, a profession which he wrote and lectured extensively about in his lifetime.
In addition, Aubrey was a managing partner of the Houston office of the international accounting firm of Alexander Grant, a Director of the Texas Society of Certified Public Accountants and Vice-President of its Houston chapter, and a National President of the Phi Beta Kappa Alumni. He also served as a member of the Auditing Task Force that assisted President Nixon's blue ribbon committee that studied the finances of the Defense Department. He has been a professor at the University of Houston and Rice University, the latter school for which he underwrote the Program in Jewish Studies postdoctoral Fellowship for 2014-2015.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains a small number of programs, certificates, booklets, and correspondence regarding imminent Jewish Associations in Houston, such as Aleph Zadik Aleph, B'nai B'rith and Emanu El, as well as personal papers related to Aubrey Farb, such as Confirmation ephemera, a book of psalms, and a framed commission from the Marine Corps, and an oral history with Aubrey and Sylvia Farb recorded in 2018. The materials are in good condition, and range in date from 1938 to 2018. They would be valuable to a researcher looking into Jewish Institutions, or specifically at the history of Aubrey and Sylvia Farb.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Susan Farb Morris donated this material in March 2018. Susan Farb Morris donated the addenda in 2020.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in three series as follows: Series I: General; Series II: Addenda; Series III: Oral History
Index Terms
Subjects
Jews and Jewish life; Social life and customs; Church bulletins; Religion
Document Types
personal correspondence; Records (documents); Records (documents); Oral histories
Subjects (Persons)
Morris, Susan Farb
- Series I: General, 1938-1991
  - Beth Israel - Aubrey Farb Confirmation Program, Certificate, and Book of Psalms, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Aleph Zadik Aleph B'nai B'rith Membership Certificate (Aubrey Farb), ca. 1940s (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Congregation Emanu El Bulletin, 1945-11-08 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Framed Commission, First Lieutenant, Marine Corps (Aubrey Farb), 1947 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Emanu El Religion School Report Card (Helene Farb), February, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Westwood Country Club Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - B'nai B'rith Women of Houston Golden Anniversary Booklet, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Series II: Addenda, 1980-2011
  - Congregation Emanu El directory, 1944-1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Program, Harold Wiesenthal roast, 1980-04-22 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Congregation Brith Shalom membership directory, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - News clippings, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - JCC Maccabi Games booklet, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Yom Lummud booklet, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - I Remember: 1897-1997 by Frances Fribourg Stillman, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Emanu El board of trustees glass paper weight, n.d. (Box 1)
- Series III: Oral History
  - Aubrey and Sylvia Farb oral history interview and transcript, 2018-04-23